<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Cable Kitten</title>
    <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Cable Kitten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Static Route</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/linux_static_route/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/linux_static_route/</guid>
      <description>Whilst recently recertifying for my LFCS the networking section had been developed and now included static routes. I thought this was fantastic. Though I know a lot of people use linux I doubt many get down into the plumbing, and work with the networking on their machines. This is just going to be a little walk through of setting up a static route.&#xA;Static routes can come in handy for connecting environments with multiple networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My LFCS Journey</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/lfcs_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/lfcs_journey/</guid>
      <description>I passed my Linux Foundation Certified Systems Administrator Exam a few weeks back. This was a recertification. Since I last took the exam the syllabus has been overhauled. Where previously you would choose between CentOS and Ubuntu, they have now gone for a vendor neutral approach.&#xA;I was hoping for the release of the new LFCE, but I fear that this is never coming. I did message the team a year ago and was told it was in development, but haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any update.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My ENCOR Journey</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/encor_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/encor_journey/</guid>
      <description>I passed my ENCOR just over a month ago. I took it on the last day of V1.0. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d give an overview of the resources I used and how I found things. Obviously the Exam has now changed, so other resources maybe required.&#xA;Resources Core Books I would read every morning as soon as I woke. This way I guaranteed that I covered something everyday regardless of what got in the way.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
