<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cable Kitten</title>
    <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cable Kitten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cablekitten.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Link Redundancy with Administrative Distance</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/link_redundancy_with_administrative_distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/link_redundancy_with_administrative_distance/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I worked through how to use EEM when we had the constraint, of having to keep the Backup circuit interface shutdown when not in use. Without this constraint we can implement redundancy with just Administrative Distance.&#xA;Administratvie Distance This is a metric that is used by vendors to rate the reliability of a route. Vendors do use different metrics. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Cisco devices in this example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EEM and a Downed Primary Circuit</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/eem_and_a_downed_primary_circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/eem_and_a_downed_primary_circuit/</guid>
      <description>The Embedded Event Manager is a brilliant tool that can be found in the Cisco IOS. Before the development of IOS-EX, devices were limited to TCL and EEM to implement scripting locally on the device. Though we now get python available to us, TCL and EEM are very useful.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m just going to roll through a simple example of using EEM. We have a Primary and a Backup Circuit in our environment, but prefer to keep the interface of the Backup circuit shutdown when the Primary is active.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Static Route</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/linux_static_route/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/linux_static_route/</guid>
      <description>Whilst recently recertifying for my LFCS the networking section had been further expanded and now included static routes. I thought this was fantastic. Though I know a lot of people use linux, I doubt many get down into the plumbing, and work with the networking on their machines. This is just going to be a little walk through of setting up a static route.&#xA;Static routes can come in handy for connecting environments with multiple networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My LFCS Journey</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/lfcs_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/lfcs_journey/</guid>
      <description>I passed my Linux Foundation Certified Systems Administrator Exam a few weeks back. This was a recertification. Since I last took the exam the syllabus has been overhauled. Where previously you would choose between CentOS and Ubuntu, they have now gone for a vendor neutral approach.&#xA;I was hoping for the release of the new LFCE, but I fear that this is never coming. I did message the team a year ago and was told it was in development, but haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any update.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/abouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 12:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/abouts/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Alick, a Network Engineer based in the UK.&#xA;I come from a background of Linux system administration and engineering, working in positions in hosting, dealing with Asterisk PBX&amp;rsquo;s, to more industrial settings with large deployments of thin clients.&#xA;A few years back though I moved into a role where I administered a large IT infrastructure of which Linux was the main OS, but the site also had a large on-site network infrastructure, plus was a hub for branch sites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My ENCOR Journey</title>
      <link>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/encor_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cablekitten.co.uk/posts/encor_journey/</guid>
      <description>I passed my ENCOR just over a month ago. I took it on the last day of V1.0. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d give an overview of the resources I used and how I found things. Obviously the Exam has now changed, so other resources maybe required.&#xA;Resources Core Books I would read every morning as soon as I woke. This way I guaranteed that I covered something everyday regardless of what got in the way.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
