<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco on Cable Kitten</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco on Cable Kitten</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cisco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GRE Tunneling Between Cisco and Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gre_tunnel_between_cisco_and_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gre_tunnel_between_cisco_and_linux/</guid>
      <description>Generic Routing Encapsulation(GRE) tunnels are a technology that was developed by Cisco but, is now an open standard through RFC 2784. GRE tunnels can provide use with a lot of versatility when needing to move different protocols between networks. Though we have now moved into an era that is predominantly TCP/IP, when GRE was developed it was at a time of multiple network technologies, IPX, Appletalk, Token Ring, etc, flourished. GRE provided the ability to encapsulate these technologies and let them traverse an Internet Protocol network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Link Redundancy with Administrative Distance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/link_redundancy_with_administrative_distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/link_redundancy_with_administrative_distance/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I worked through how to use EEM when we had the constraint, of having to keep the Backup circuit interface shutdown when not in use. Without this constraint we can implement redundancy with just Administrative Distance.&#xA;Administratvie Distance This is a metric that is used by vendors to rate the reliability of a route. Vendors do use different metrics. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Cisco devices in this example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EEM and a Downed Primary Circuit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/eem_and_a_downed_primary_circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/eem_and_a_downed_primary_circuit/</guid>
      <description>The Embedded Event Manager is a brilliant tool that can be found in the Cisco IOS. Before the development of IOS-EX, devices were limited to TCL and EEM to implement scripting locally on the device. Though we now get python available to us, TCL and EEM are still very useful.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m just going to roll through a simple example of using EEM. We have a Primary and a Backup Circuit in our environment, but prefer to keep the interface of the Backup circuit shutdown when the Primary is active.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Cisco ENCOR Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/encor_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/encor_journey/</guid>
      <description>I passed my Cisco ENCOR exam just over a month ago. I took it on the last day of V1.0. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d give an overview of the resources I used and how I found things. Obviously the Exam has now changed, so other resources maybe required.&#xA;Resources Core Books I would read every morning as soon as I woke. This way I guaranteed that I covered something everyday regardless of what got in the way.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
